<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
 <!--
   Copyright 2005-2006 Log4Delphi Project

   Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
   you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
   You may obtain a copy of the License at

       http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

   Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
   distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
   WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
   See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
   limitations under the License.
  -->
<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC "-//APACHE//DTD Documentation V1.2//EN" 
          "http://apache.org/forrest/dtd/document-v12.dtd">
          
<document> 
    <header>
        <title>Download Releases of Log4Delphi</title>
    </header>
    <body>
        <section>
            <title>Official Log4Delphi Releases</title>
            <p>Official Source and Binary Packages can be found 
				<link href="https://sourceforge.net/project/showfiles.php?group_id=145326">
					here</link>.</p>            
        </section>
        <section>
        	<title>Verifying the Archive Integrity</title>
        	<p>Each archive in the file release section has an accompanying MD5 
        	file which has the same name of the archive it verifies with the 
        	<code>.MD5</code> extension. The MD5 file is a checksum of the 
        	archive generated at the same time that the archive is created, 
        	both files are then uploaded securely to the server. The MD5 file 
        	should be used to ensure the archive's integrity.</p>
        	<section>
        		<title>Windows</title>
        		<p>To verify the integrity of an archive using an MD5 checksum on
        		Windows requires a utility to do so. A free command line utlity
        		is available from: <link href="http://www.fourmilab.ch/md5/">
        		   http://www.fourmilab.ch/md5/</link>. Download the utility
        		   from this page, extract the archive to the location of your 
        		   choice and include the <code>md5.exe</code> file in your PATH 
				   variable.
        		</p>
        		<p> You can verify the contents of an archive by running the
        		utility in the command line and passing it the archive as a command
				line parameter, it will	print the MD5 sum which you can check against 
				the MD5 checksum given in the MD5 file. As an example the utility was 
				run on a binary distribution and the MD5 file's contents printed to the
        		screen using the <code>more</code> command. The checksums are
        		identical.
        		</p>
        		<source>
F:\Development\log4delphi\dist\0.1>md5 log4delphi-0.1-bin.tar.gz
D82AF52C3B33A1A90A4626A48914ACC5  log4delphi-0.1-bin.tar.gz

F:\Development\log4delphi\dist\0.1>more log4delphi-0.1-bin.tar.gz.MD5
d82af52c3b33a1a90a4626a48914acc6       		
        		</source>
        	</section>
        	<section>
        		<title>Linux</title>
        		<p>Many linux distributions include the <code>md5</code> command 
        		line utility that can be used to verify the archive against the 
        		MD5 checksum. The md5 utility is part of the Open SSL package
				which needs to be installed on your machine.</p>
				<p>You can verify the contents of an archive by running the utility
					in the command line and passing the archive as a command line 
					parameter, it will print the md5 sum which you can check against
					the MD5 checksum given in the MD5 file. As an example, the utility
					was run on a binary distribution and the MD5 file's contents printed 
					using the <code>cat</code> command. The checksums are identical.</p>
        		<source>
[trevor@woodstock 0.1]$ cat log4delphi-0.1-bin.tar.gz.MD5
d82af52c3b33a1a90a4626a48914acc6
[trevor@woodstock 0.1]$ openssl md5 log4delphi-0.1-bin.tar.gz
MD5(log4delphi-0.1-bin.tar.gz)= d82af52c3b33a1a90a4626a48914acc5
        		</source>
        	</section>        	
        </section>
    </body>
    <footer>
    	<legal>Copyright 2005-2006 Log4Delphi Project. All Rights Reserved.</legal>
    </footer>
</document>