<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
 <!--
   Copyright 2005-2006 Log4Delphi Project

   Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
   you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
   You may obtain a copy of the License at

       http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

   Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
   distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
   WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
   See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
   limitations under the License.
  -->

<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC "-//APACHE//DTD Documentation V1.2//EN" 
          "http://apache.org/forrest/dtd/document-v12.dtd">
<document> 
    <header>
        <title>Frequently Asked Questions about Log4Delphi</title>
    </header>
    <body>
        <section>
            <title>Questions</title>
			<section>				
				<title>Getting Started and Building Log4Delphi</title>
				<section>
					<title>What versions of Delphi does Log4Delphi support?</title>
					<p>Log4Delphi is developed on Delphi 6 Enterprise and has been
						made to compile on Delphi 5. It is assumed that later
						versions of Delphi should work. Prior versions will most
						likely run into errors. We will release packages for
						prior versions of Delphi in later versions of Log4Delphi.</p>
				</section>
				<section>
					<title>Where can I read an overview about how to work with 
						Log4Delphi?</title>
					<p>See the <link href="getstarted.html">Getting Started</link> 
						guide.</p>
				</section>
				<section>
					<title>Which version of Log4Delphi does the website documentation 
						relate to?</title>
					<p>The latest stable release, by using the latest release the
						information contained on the website will be relevant.</p>
				</section>	
				<section>
					<title>How can I use CVS to keep up to date with the latest 
						codebase?</title>
					<p>See the <link href="cvs.html">CVS</link> guide.</p>
				</section>				
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Technical</title>
				<section>
					<title>Does It Run On Linux?</title>
					<p>Log4Delphi is generic enough to be compiled on Kylix. Although 
						this has not yet been tested it should work without error.</p>
				</section>
				<section>
					<title>What is the MD5 file in the file releases?</title>
					<p>The MD5 file is a text file that contains an MD5 checksum
						of the corresponding archive generated at the same time that the 
						archive	was created. It is used to ensure the integrity of the
						downloaded archive. For more information see the 
						<link href="download.html">Download</link> page.</p>
				</section>			
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Older Versions</title>
				<section>
					<title>How can I upgrade to the latest version?</title>
					<p>It depends how you installed the previous version. If you 
						installed the package it is recommended to first uninstall it 
						before proceeding to install the new package. If, however, you 
						simply copied the source code into your project's code base, 
						then simply overwriting them with the newer source files should 
						work. See the <link href="userguide.html">User Guide</link>
						for specific instructions.</p>
				</section>						
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>General</title>
				<section>
					<title>Where are the log files to find more infomation about 
						errors?</title>
					<p>Log4Delphi's internal logging will send log output to a file 
						named <code>log4delphi.log</code> in the current directory of 
						your application, this will typically be the directory from 
						which your application gets run. You can control this feature
						using the <code>log4delphi.debug</code> directive in a properties
						configuration file. See the <link href="userguide.html">User Guide</link> 
						for more information.</p>
				</section>	
				<section>
					<title>How can I help or contribute?</title>
					<p> Join one of the Log4Delphi project 
						<link href="contact.html">mailing lists</link>  and tell us what 
						you would like to see improved. We regard all feedback as 
						valuable, particularly from newcomers—often, close proximity 
						blinds software developers to faults that are obvious to everyone 
						else. Don't be shy!</p>
				</section>
				<section>
					<title>Why create new logging project for Delphi? Analogous project Log4D already exists?</title>
					<p> Log4D last updated their CVS 16 Months ago, the project has had no recent
						activity since then. They also have no file releases which means new users
						would have to get source code from the CVS repository which is not good.
					</p><p>
						Log4D is also a direct port of Log4J while Log4Delphi is loosely based on
						Log4J which means that Log4Delphi does not have to follow what Log4J is
						doing, we can deviate from log4j at any time, which is a good thing,
						considering the numerous differences between Java and Delphi.</p>						
				</section>				
			</section>
		</section>
	</body>
	<footer>
    	<legal>Copyright 2005-2006 Log4Delphi Project. All Rights Reserved.</legal>
    </footer>
</document>					